Matthew James Tootell

email: matttootell@hotmail.com telephone: 07708 810680 website: https://miraematt.github.io/newwebsite

Profile

A Software Developer who has recently graduated from the Northcoders full stack training programme. With a background in education, having run his own successful language academy in South Korea for over ten years, he has returned to the Lancashire area to begin a new career in IT.

Technical Skills

Languages: Javascript with prior experience in Python.

Back-end: Node.js, Express, Axios, AWS(Lambda, API Gateway and DynamoDB), PostgreSQL, SQLite, Server

less, Knex, Flask.

Front-end: React.js, HTML, CSS, Sass, jQuery. **Testing**: Mocha, Chai, Jest, Supertest.

Experience

2019 Trainee Developer, Northcoders Full-Stack Coding Bootcamp

Using Javascript. Backend projects were completed with the aid of Node.js, Express, Axios, PostgreSQL and Knex. Frontend work utilised React.js, HTML 5, CSS and SASS. Emphasis was placed on using full TDD throughout, with Mocha, Chai, Supertest and Jest. Extensive use of git and github, while working closely with a partner during two day sprints.

Northcoders Projects. NC News: Full-stack news and comments board. Articles and comments can be post-

ed, read and deleted. The website is fully responsive using vanilla CSS styling. Fully deployed web version: https://mattsncnewsproject.netlify.com

Front-end/Back-end repositories: https://github.com/miraematt/ncnews-front-end

https://github.com/miraematt/b-end-ncnews-project

Back-end API hosting: https://mattsncnewsproject.herokuapp.com/api

Final Project (ongoing): As a member of a team of five Northcoders students, played a key role in formulating and implementing a full stack mobile app. Using AWS Lambda, Serverless, DynamoDB, React.js and Axios.

Other Programming Experience

2018: Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python.

MITx - 6.00.1x through edX. Certificate with 97% final grade.

2017: CS50's Introduction to Computer Science. Using C, Javascript and Python. Final project involving

Flask and Jinja. HarvardX - CS50 through edX. Certificate with 100% final grade.

2016: Codecademy online courses at www.codecademy.com. Completed courses and projects in HTML

and CSS, SASS, Javascript, jQuery, Python, git and using the Command Line.

Previous Work Experience

2008 - 2019 Co-owner and Teacher, Mirae English Academy, Pyeongtaek, South Korea

Involved in every aspect of the business, from teaching up to thirty-two classes a week, to creating a curriculum and conducting monthly student evaluations. Students often stayed with our academy throughout elementary and middle school, while several alumni have gone on to study at prestigious high schools and universities in South Korea.

2004 - 2008 English Teacher, Naegi Elementary School, Pyeongtaek si, South Korea

Co-taught classes of 35 students alongside a Korean English teacher in a public elementary school. This involved working fluidly as part of a team along with my co-teachers. National testing showed a marked improvement in the English ability of students after four years.

2003 English Instructor, Kukje Language Academy, Suwon, South Korea

Taught English to employees at companies including Samsung and General Electric. Companies specifically asked for me to teach their employees, praising my rapport with the students and class presentation skills.

2002 Account Manager, Thomas Computer Supplies Ltd., Leyland, Lancashire

Maintained the accounts of businesses across the North West. Exceeded my sales target by more than 20% for each of my final four months.

2001 Account Executive, iForce Ltd., Erdington, Birmingham

Gained valuable experience at a large logistics company. Responsible for the distribution and maintenance of stock for international companies including Vauxhall and British American Tobacco, working on iForce's own warehouse management software, SMART.

2000 Administrator, SATRO, University of Birmingham, Birmingham

Education

1996 - 2000 Degree: University of Birmingham

BSc. Mathematical Science with Study in Continental Europe

3rd Class Honours

1996 A-Levels: Bolton School

Further Mathematics (A), Mathematics (A), Physics (A),

Chemistry(A), General Studies (A)

1994 GCSEs: A* (3), A (8) including English (A), Mathematics (A*) and Art (A)

Further Information

Sports: Captained the university mathematics football team for two years with full responsibilities regarding training sessions and trials, refereeing and purchasing equipment for one 11-a-side and two six-a-side teams. We became the most successful departmental team, winning every competition.

Languages: Conversational in French and Korean.

Overseas: An experienced traveller with a unique point of view having worked and spent lengths of time in a number of different countries. Notably:

1998/99: Studied mathematics for a year at Claude Bernard University, Lyon, France.

2000 and 2002: Taught football at Camp Harlam summer camp, Pennsylvania, USA.

2002: Studied for one month in Guadalajara, Mexico, to earn a TEFL(Teaching English as a Foreign Language) Certificate.

2002/3: Spent seven months travelling overland from New York to Panama City.

2003 - 2019.: Lived in South Korea for sixteen years.